[
  {
    "id": 1,
    "question": "The first instruction of \"COM\" file must be at offset:",
    "options": ["0x0010", "0x0100", "0x1000", "0x0000"],
    "correct": "0x0100",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "importance": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 2,
    "question": "The execution of the instruction \"mov word [ES: 0], 0x0741\" will print character \"A\" on screen, background color of the screen will be",
    "options": ["Black", "White", "Red", "Blue"],
    "correct": "Black",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "importance": 2
  },
  {
    "id": 3,
    "question": "The iAPX888 architecture consists of ______ register.",
    "options": ["12", "14", "16", "18"],
    "correct": "16",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "importance": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 4,
    "question": "The execution of the instruction \"mov word [ES: 0], 0x0741\" will print \"A\" on the screen, color of the character will be",
    "options": ["Black", "White", "Red", "Blue"],
    "correct": "White",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "importance": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 5,
    "question": "One screen location corresponds to a",
    "options": ["Byte", "Word", "Double byte", "Double word"],
    "correct": "Word",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "importance": 4
  },
  {
    "id": 6,
    "question": "When an item is pushed on the decrementing stack, the top of the stack is",
    "options": [
      "First decremented and then element copied on to the stack",
      "First incremented and then element copied on to the stack",
      "Decremented after the element copied on to the stack",
      "Incremented after the element copied on to the stack"
    ],
    "correct": "First decremented and then element copied on to the stack",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "importance": 5
  },
  {
    "id": 7,
    "question": "Each screen location corresponds to a word, the lower byte of this word contains",
    "options": [
      "The character code",
      "The attribute byte",
      "The parameters",
      "The dimensions"
    ],
    "correct": "The character code",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "importance": 2
  },
  {
    "id": 8,
    "question": "if ax contains decimal -2 and BX contains decimal 2 then after the execution of instructions: CMP AX, BX,JA label",
    "options": [
      "Jump will be taken",
      "Zero flag will set",
      "ZF will contain value -4",
      "Jump will not be taken"
    ],
    "correct": "Jump will not be taken",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "importance": 3
  },
  {
    "id": 9,
    "question": "If D is \"35\" is shift to left 2 bits the new value",
    "options": ["35", "70", "140", "17"],
    "correct": "140",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "importance": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 10,
    "question": "When two 16bit numbers are added the answer can be 17 bits long, this extra bit that won't fit in the target register is placed in the where it can be used and tested",
    "options": ["carry flag", "Parity Flag", "Auxiliary Carry", "Zero Flag"],
    "correct": "carry flag",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "importance": 4
  },
  {
    "id": 11,
    "question": "Only ______ instructions allow moving data from memory to memory.",
    "options": ["string", "word", "indirect", "stack"],
    "correct": "string",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "importance": 5
  },
  {
    "id": 12,
    "question": "When a 16 bit number is divided by an 8 bit number, the quotient will be in",
    "options": ["AL", "AX", "AH", "DX"],
    "correct": "AL",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "importance": 4
  },
  {
    "id": 13,
    "question": "Which bit of the attributes byte represents the red component of background color ?",
    "options": ["3", "4", "5", "6"],
    "correct": "6",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "importance": 2
  },
  {
    "id": 14,
    "question": "|0|-->|1|1|0|1| 0 | 0 | 0 |-- | C | is a example of",
    "options": ["Shl", "sar", "Shr", "Sal"],
    "correct": "Shr",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "importance": 4
  },
  {
    "id": 15,
    "question": "______ allow changing specific processor behaviors and are used to play with it.",
    "options": [
      "Special Instructions",
      "Data Movement Instructions",
      "Program Control Instructions",
      "Arithmetic and Logic Instructions"
    ],
    "correct": "Special Instructions",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "importance": 4
  },
  {
    "id": 16,
    "question": "8088 is a 16bit processor with its accumulator and all registers of",
    "options": ["32 bits", "6 bits", "16 bits", "64 bits"],
    "correct": "16 bits",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "importance": 4
  },
  {
    "id": 17,
    "question": "______ decrements SP (the stack pointer) by two and then transfers a word from the source operand to the top of stack",
    "options": ["PUSH", "POP", "CALL", "RET"],
    "correct": "PUSH",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "importance": 2
  },
  {
    "id": 18,
    "question": "In instruction ADC the operands can be",
    "options": [
      "Two register only",
      "Two register and one memory location",
      "CF and two other operands",
      "ZF and two other operands"
    ],
    "correct": "CF and two other operands",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "importance": 2
  },
  {
    "id": 19,
    "question": "After the execution of instruction \"RET\"",
    "options": [
      "SP is incremented by 2",
      "SP is decremented by 2",
      "SP is incremented by 1",
      "SP is decremented by 1"
    ],
    "correct": "SP is incremented by 2",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "importance": 2
  },
  {
    "id": 20,
    "question": "The extended ASCII has",
    "options": [
      "64 characters",
      "128 characters",
      "256 characters",
      "502 characters"
    ],
    "correct": "256 characters",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "importance": 4
  },
  {
    "id": 21,
    "question": "The second byte in the word designated for screen location holds",
    "options": [
      "The dimension of the screen",
      "Character position on the screen",
      "Character color on the screen",
      "ACSII code of the character"
    ],
    "correct": "Character color on the screen",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "importance": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 22,
    "question": "REP will always",
    "options": [
      "Incremented CX by 1",
      "Incremented CX by 2",
      "Decremented CX by 1",
      "Decremented CX by 2"
    ],
    "correct": "Decremented CX by 1",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "importance": 2
  },
  {
    "id": 23,
    "question": "The routine that executes in response to an INT instruction is called",
    "options": ["ISR", "IRS", "ISP", "IRT"],
    "correct": "ISR",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "importance": 2
  },
  {
    "id": 24,
    "question": "The iAPX888 architecture consists of ______ register.",
    "options": ["12", "14", "16", "18"],
    "correct": "16",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "importance": 3
  },
  {
    "id": 25,
    "question": "In the instruction \"CMP AX,BX\" the contents of",
    "options": [
      "AX are changed",
      "BX are changed",
      "CX are changed",
      "Flag register are changed"
    ],
    "correct": "Flag register are changed",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "importance": 5
  },
  {
    "id": 26,
    "question": "All the addressing mechanisms in iAPX88 return a number called ______ address.",
    "options": ["Effective", "faulty", "indirect", "direct"],
    "correct": "Effective",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "importance": 4
  },
  {
    "id": 27,
    "question": "The execution of the instruction \"mov word [ES: DI], 0x0720\"",
    "options": [
      "will clear next character on screen",
      "will print \"20\" at top left of the screen",
      "will print \"20\" at top right of the screen",
      "will move DI at location 0720 on the screen"
    ],
    "correct": "will clear next character on screen",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "importance": 3
  },
  {
    "id": 28,
    "question": "\"mov byte [num1],5\" is ______ instruction.",
    "options": ["legal", "illegal", "stack based", "memory indirect"],
    "correct": "legal",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "importance": 5
  },
  {
    "id": 29,
    "question": "MOV instruction transfers a byte or word from which of the following source location.",
    "options": ["DS:DI", "ES:SI", "ES:DI", "DS:SI"],
    "correct": "DS:SI",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "importance": 2
  },
  {
    "id": 30,
    "question": "The execution of the instruction \"mov word [ES: 0], 0x0741\" will print \"A\" on the screen, color of the character will be",
    "options": ["Black", "White", "Red", "Blue"],
    "correct": "White",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "importance": 4
  },
  {
    "id": 31,
    "question": "If AX contains FFFFh, then after execution of instruction \"SAL ax, 3\", the result will be",
    "options": ["0-3", "+3", "0-8", "+8"],
    "correct": "0-8",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "importance": 2
  },
  {
    "id": 32,
    "question": "If the decimal number \"35\" is shifted by two bit to left, the new value will be",
    "options": ["35", "70", "140", "17"],
    "correct": "140",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "importance": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 33,
    "question": "While using STOBS, if $DF=1$ then",
    "options": [
      "The value of SI will be incremented by one",
      "The value of SI will be incremented by two",
      "The value of SI will be decremented by one",
      "The value of SI will be decremented by two"
    ],
    "correct": "The value of SI will be decremented by one",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "importance": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 34,
    "question": "After the execution of STOSW, the CX will be",
    "options": [
      "Decremented by 1",
      "Decremented by 2",
      "Incremented by 1",
      "Incremented by 2"
    ],
    "correct": "Decremented by 1",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "importance": 4
  },
  {
    "id": 35,
    "question": "The memory address always move from",
    "options": [
      "processor to memory",
      "memory to processor",
      "memory to peripheral",
      "peripheral to processor"
    ],
    "correct": "processor to memory",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "importance": 2
  },
  {
    "id": 36,
    "question": "An offset alone is not complete without",
    "options": ["Segment", "code label", "index register", "data label"],
    "correct": "Segment",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "importance": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 37,
    "question": "Code Segment is associated to ______ register by default.",
    "options": ["IP", "SS", "BP", "CX"],
    "correct": "IP",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "importance": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 38,
    "question": "After the execution of SAR instruction:",
    "options": [
      "MSB remain as it is",
      "MSB Will change",
      "MSB move to left",
      "No change will occur."
    ],
    "correct": "MSB remain as it is",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "importance": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 39,
    "question": "The screen is two dimensional space having:",
    "options": [
      "25 Rows and 25 Columns",
      "25 Rows and 80 Columns",
      "80 Rows and 80 Columns",
      "80 Rows and 25 Columns"
    ],
    "correct": "25 Rows and 80 Columns",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "importance": 4
  },
  {
    "id": 40,
    "question": "In the Rotate Right Operation every bit moves one position to right and the bit dropped from the right is inserted at the left and:",
    "options": ["Dropped in CF", "moves to AL", "Don't go anywhere."],
    "correct": "Dropped in CF",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "importance": 2
  },
  {
    "id": 41,
    "question": "______ of the following flags will be affected by MOVSB?",
    "options": ["DF", "ZF", "PF", "No effect on flags."],
    "correct": "DF",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "importance": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 42,
    "question": "The iAPX88 processor supports ______ modes of memory access.",
    "options": ["5", "6", "7", "8-"],
    "correct": "7",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "importance": 5
  },
  {
    "id": 43,
    "question": "Stack is a ______ that behaves in a first in last out manner.",
    "options": ["Program", "data structure", "Heap", "None of the Given"],
    "correct": "data structure",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "importance": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 44,
    "question": "The physical address of the stack is obtained by",
    "options": [
      "SS:SI combination",
      "SS:SP combination",
      "ES:BP combination",
      "ES:SP combination"
    ],
    "correct": "SS:SP combination",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "importance": 3
  },
  {
    "id": 45,
    "question": "Foreground and background parameter will be",
    "options": ["32bits", "16bits", "8bits", "4bits"],
    "correct": "8bits",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "importance": 2
  },
  {
    "id": 46,
    "question": "The clear screen operation initialize whole block of memory",
    "options": ["0741", "0417", "0714", "0174,0720"],
    "correct": "0720",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "importance": 3
  },
  {
    "id": 47,
    "question": "In STOSB instruction, when DF is Set, SI is",
    "options": [
      "Incremented by 1",
      "Incremented by 2",
      "Decremented by 1",
      "Decremented by 2"
    ],
    "correct": "Decremented by 1",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "importance": 5
  },
  {
    "id": 48,
    "question": "Assembly language is:",
    "options": [
      "Low-level programming language",
      "High-level programming language",
      "Also known as machine language",
      "Not considered closer to the computer"
    ],
    "correct": "Low-level programming language",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "importance": 5
  },
  {
    "id": 49,
    "question": "A 32 Bit processor has accumulator of",
    "options": ["8 bit", "16 bit", "32 bit", "64 bit"],
    "correct": "32 bit",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "importance": 2
  },
  {
    "id": 50,
    "question": "To transfer control back the RET instruction take",
    "options": ["1 argument", "1 argument", "3 arguments", "No arguments"],
    "correct": "No arguments",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "importance": 5
  },
  {
    "id": 51,
    "question": "RET is executed, it recovers the values from",
    "options": ["Register", "Stack", "Data segment", "Code segment"],
    "correct": "Stack",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "importance": 4
  },
  {
    "id": 52,
    "question": "To convert any digit to its ASCII representation",
    "options": [
      "Add 0x30 in the digit",
      "Subtract 0x30 from the digit",
      "Add 0x61 in the digit",
      "Subtract 0x61 from the digit"
    ],
    "correct": "Add 0x30 in the digit",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "importance": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 53,
    "question": "The prevalent convention in most high level languages is stack clearing by the",
    "options": ["Caller", "Callee", "RET", "Stack"],
    "correct": "Caller",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "importance": 3
  },
  {
    "id": 54,
    "question": "After execution of JCXZ instruction CX will changed with flag affect.",
    "options": ["CF", "OF", "DF", "None of Above"],
    "correct": "None of Above",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "importance": 3
  },
  {
    "id": 55,
    "question": "Execution of the instruction \"mov word [ES: 0], 0x0741\" will print",
    "options": [
      "\"A\" appear on the top left of screen",
      "\"A\" appear on the top right of screen",
      "\"A\" appear on the center of screen",
      "\"A\" appear on the bottom left of screen"
    ],
    "correct": "\"A\" appear on the top left of screen",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "importance": 4
  },
  {
    "id": 56,
    "question": "if contains decimal -2 and BX contains decimal 2 then after the execution of instructions: CMP AX, BX JA label",
    "options": [
      "Jump will be taken",
      "Zero flag will set",
      "ZF will contain value -4",
      "Jump will not be taken"
    ],
    "correct": "Jump will not be taken",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "importance": 4
  },
  {
    "id": 57,
    "question": "Which of the following options contain the set of instructions to open a window to the video memory?",
    "options": [
      "mov AX, 0xb008 mov ES, AX",
      "mov AX, 0xb800 mov ES, AX",
      "mov AX, 0x8b00 mov ES, AX",
      "mov AX, 0x800b mov ES, AX"
    ],
    "correct": "mov AX, 0xb800 mov ES, AX",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "importance": 5
  },
  {
    "id": 58,
    "question": "If D is \"35\" is shift to left 2 bits the new value",
    "options": ["35", "70", "140", "17"],
    "correct": "140",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "importance": 5
  },
  {
    "id": 59,
    "question": "Execution of the instruction \"mov word [ES: 0], 0x1230\" will print the character color will",
    "options": ["Green", "White", "Red", "Black"],
    "correct": "Red",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "importance": 2
  },
  {
    "id": 60,
    "question": "After the execution of SAR instruction",
    "options": [
      "The msb is replaced by a 0",
      "The msb is replaced by 1",
      "The msb retains its original value",
      "The msb is replaced by the value of CF (Page 52)"
    ],
    "correct": "The msb retains its original value",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "importance": 4
  },
  {
    "id": 61,
    "question": "RETF will pop the offset in the",
    "options": ["BP", "IP", "SP", "SI"],
    "correct": "IP",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "importance": 3
  },
  {
    "id": 62,
    "question": "The routine that executes in response to an INT instruction is called",
    "options": ["ISR", "IRS", "ISP", "IRT"],
    "correct": "ISR",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "importance": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 63,
    "question": "The first instruction of \"COM\" file must be at offset:",
    "options": ["0x0010", "0x0100", "0x1000", "0x0000"],
    "correct": "0x0100",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "importance": 2
  },
  {
    "id": 64,
    "question": "\"Far\" jump is not position relative but is",
    "options": ["memory dependent", "Absolute", "Temporary", "indirect"],
    "correct": "Absolute",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "importance": 4
  },
  {
    "id": 65,
    "question": "Only ______ instructions allow moving data from memory to memory.",
    "options": ["string", "word", "indirect", "stack"],
    "correct": "string",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "importance": 2
  },
  {
    "id": 66,
    "question": "After the execution of instruction \"RET 2\"",
    "options": [
      "SP is incremented by 2",
      "SP is decremented by 2",
      "SP is incremented by 4 (Page 66)",
      "SP is decremented by 4"
    ],
    "correct": "SP is incremented by 4 (Page 66)",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "importance": 4
  },
  {
    "id": 67,
    "question": "DIV instruction has",
    "options": ["Two forms", "Three forms", "Four forms", "Five forms"],
    "correct": "Two forms",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "importance": 5
  },
  {
    "id": 68,
    "question": "When the operand of DIV instruction is of 16 bits then implied dividend will be of",
    "options": ["8 bits", "16 bits", "32 bits", "64 bits"],
    "correct": "32 bits",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "importance": 4
  },
  {
    "id": 69,
    "question": "After the execution of MOVS instruction which of the following registers are updated",
    "options": ["SI only", "DI only", "SI and DI only", "SI, DI and BP only"],
    "correct": "SI and DI only",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "importance": 3
  },
  {
    "id": 70,
    "question": "In 8088 architecture, whenever an element is pushed on the stack",
    "options": [
      "SP is decremented by 1",
      "SP is decremented by 2",
      "SP is decremented by 3",
      "SP is decremented by 4"
    ],
    "correct": "SP is decremented by 2",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "importance": 2
  },
  {
    "id": 71,
    "question": "When a very large number is divided by very small number so that the quotient is larger than the space provided, this is called",
    "options": [
      "Divide logical error",
      "Divide overflow error",
      "Divide syntax error",
      "An illegal instruction"
    ],
    "correct": "Divide overflow error",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "importance": 4
  },
  {
    "id": 72,
    "question": "In the word designated for one screen location, the higher address contains",
    "options": [
      "The character code",
      "The attribute byte",
      "The parameters",
      "The dimensions"
    ],
    "correct": "The attribute byte",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "importance": 2
  },
  {
    "id": 73,
    "question": "Which of the following options contain the set of instructions to open a window to the video memory?",
    "options": [
      "mov AX, 0xb008 mov ES, AX",
      "mov AX, 0xb800 mov ES, AX",
      "mov AX, 0x8b00 mov ES, AX",
      "mov AX, 0x800b mov ES, AX"
    ],
    "correct": "mov AX, 0xb800 mov ES, AX",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "importance": 2
  },
  {
    "id": 74,
    "question": "In a video memory, each screen location corresponds to",
    "options": ["One byte", "Two bytes", "Four bytes", "Eight bytes"],
    "correct": "Two bytes",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "importance": 5
  },
  {
    "id": 75,
    "question": "The execution of the instruction \"mov word [ES: 0], 0x0741\" will print character \"A\" on screen, background color of the screen will be",
    "options": ["Black", "White", "Red", "Blue"],
    "correct": "Black",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "importance": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 76,
    "question": "One screen location corresponds to a",
    "options": ["Byte", "Word", "Double byte", "Double word"],
    "correct": "Word",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "importance": 4
  },
  {
    "id": 77,
    "question": "After the execution of \"PUSH AX\" statement",
    "options": [
      "AX register will reside on the stack",
      "A copy of AX will go on the stack",
      "The value of AX disappear after moving on stack",
      "Stack will send an acceptance message"
    ],
    "correct": "A copy of AX will go on the stack",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "importance": 5
  },
  {
    "id": 78,
    "question": "physical address of the stack is obtained by",
    "options": [
      "SS:SP combination",
      "SS:SI combination",
      "SS:SP combination",
      "ES:BP combination",
      "ES:SP combination"
    ],
    "correct": "SS:SP combination",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "importance": 2
  },
  {
    "id": 79,
    "question": "If the address of memory location Num1 is 0117 and its content is 0005 then after execution of the instruction \"mov bx, Numl\" bx will contain",
    "options": ["0005", "0117", "Num1", "1701"],
    "correct": "0005",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "importance": 5
  },
  {
    "id": 80,
    "question": "In STOS instruction, the implied source will always be in",
    "options": [
      "AL or AX registers",
      "DL or DX registers",
      "BL or BX registers",
      "CL or CX registers"
    ],
    "correct": "AL or AX registers",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "importance": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 81,
    "question": "The shift logical right operation inserts",
    "options": [
      "A zero at right",
      "A zero at left",
      "A one at right",
      "A one at right"
    ],
    "correct": "A zero at left",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "importance": 5
  },
  {
    "id": 82,
    "question": "REP will always",
    "options": [
      "Increment CX by 1",
      "Increment CX by 2",
      "Decrement CX by 1",
      "Decrement CX by 2"
    ],
    "correct": "Decrement CX by 1",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "importance": 5
  },
  {
    "id": 83,
    "question": "When an item is pushed on the decrementing stack, the top of the stack is",
    "options": [
      "First decremented and then element copied on to the stack",
      "First incremented and then element copied on to the stack",
      "Decremented after the element copied on to the stack",
      "Incremented after the element copied on to the stack"
    ],
    "correct": "First decremented and then element copied on to the stack",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "importance": 3
  },
  {
    "id": 84,
    "question": "In assembly the CX register is used normally as a ______ register.",
    "options": ["source", "counter", "index", "pointer"],
    "correct": "counter",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "importance": 2
  },
  {
    "id": 85,
    "question": "Which is the unidirectional bus ?",
    "options": [
      "(I) Control Bus",
      "(II) Data Bus",
      "(III) Address Bus",
      "I only",
      "II only",
      "III only",
      "I and II only"
    ],
    "correct": "III only",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "importance": 4
  },
  {
    "id": 86,
    "question": "The basic function of SCAS instruction is to",
    "options": ["Compare", "Scan", "Sort", "Move data"],
    "correct": "Compare",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "importance": 5
  },
  {
    "id": 87,
    "question": "______ register holds the address of next instruction is to be executed",
    "options": [
      "Base pointer",
      "Code segment",
      "Source index",
      "Program counter"
    ],
    "correct": "Program counter",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "importance": 2
  },
  {
    "id": 88,
    "question": "JC and JNC test the ______ flag.",
    "options": ["carry", "parity", "zero", "sign"],
    "correct": "carry",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "importance": 4
  },
  {
    "id": 89,
    "question": "After the execution of REP instruction CX will be decremented then which of the following flags will be affected?",
    "options": ["CF", "OF", "DF", "No flags will be affected"],
    "correct": "No flags will be affected",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "importance": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 90,
    "question": "In string manipulation whenever an instruction needs a memory source, which of the following will hold the pointer to it?",
    "options": ["ES: DI", "ES: BP", "DS:BP", "DS:SI"],
    "correct": "DS:SI",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "importance": 3
  },
  {
    "id": 91,
    "question": "which bit sets the character \"blinking\" on the screen?",
    "options": ["5", "6", "5678", "7"],
    "correct": "7",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "importance": 3
  },
  {
    "id": 92,
    "question": "If we want to divide a signed number by 2, this operation can better be accomplished by",
    "options": ["SHR", "SAR", "SHL", "SAL"],
    "correct": "SAR",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "importance": 3
  },
  {
    "id": 93,
    "question": "After the execution of STOSB, the CX wil be.",
    "options": [
      "Incremented by 1",
      "Incremented by 2",
      "Decremented by 1",
      "Decremented by 2"
    ],
    "correct": "Decremented by 1",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "importance": 3
  },
  {
    "id": 94,
    "question": "Each screen location corresponds to a word, the lower byte of this word contains",
    "options": [
      "The character code",
      "The attribute byte",
      "The parameters",
      "The dimensions"
    ],
    "correct": "The character code",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "importance": 2
  },
  {
    "id": 95,
    "question": "In a video memory, each screen location corresponds to",
    "options": ["One byte", "Two bytes", "Four bytes", "Eight bytes"],
    "correct": "Two bytes",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "importance": 4
  },
  {
    "id": 96,
    "question": "Execution of the instruction \"mov word [ES: 0], 0x0741\" will print",
    "options": [
      "\"A\" appear on the top left of screen",
      "\"A\" appear on the top right of screen",
      "\"A\" appear on the center of screen",
      "\"A\" appear on the bottom left of screen"
    ],
    "correct": "\"A\" appear on the top left of screen",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "importance": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 97,
    "question": "After the execution of \"PUSH AX\" statement",
    "options": [
      "AX register will reside on the stack",
      "A copy of AX will go on the stack",
      "The value of AX disappear after moving on stack",
      "Stack will send an acceptance message"
    ],
    "correct": "A copy of AX will go on the stack",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "importance": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 98,
    "question": "If D is \"35\" is shift to left 2 bits the new value",
    "options": ["35", "70", "140", "17"],
    "correct": "140",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "importance": 2
  },
  {
    "id": 99,
    "question": "When an item is pushed on the decrementing stack, the top of the stack is",
    "options": [
      "First decremented and then element copied on to the stack",
      "First incremented and then element copied on to the stack",
      "Decremented after the element copied on to the stack",
      "Incremented after the element copied on to the stack"
    ],
    "correct": "First decremented and then element copied on to the stack",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "importance": 2
  },
  {
    "id": 100,
    "question": "After the execution of REP instruction CX will be decremented then which of the following flags will be affected?",
    "options": ["CF", "OF", "DF", "No flags will be affected"],
    "correct": "No flags will be affected",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "importance": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 101,
    "question": "In a video memory, each screen location corresponds to",
    "options": ["One byte", "Two bytes", "Four bytes", "Eight bytes"],
    "correct": "Two bytes",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "importance": 3
  },
  {
    "id": 102,
    "question": "shifting the -15 two bit SAR",
    "options": ["-7", "-8", "7", "78"],
    "correct": "-8",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "importance": 3
  },
  {
    "id": 103,
    "question": "mov ax,5 has",
    "options": ["1 operand", "2 opeand", "3 operand", "4 opeand"],
    "correct": "2 opeand",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "importance": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 104,
    "question": "The physical address of the stack is obtained by",
    "options": [
      "SS:SP combination",
      "SS:SI combination",
      "SS:SP combination",
      "ES:BP combination",
      "ES:SP combination"
    ],
    "correct": "SS:SP combination",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "importance": 5
  },
  {
    "id": 105,
    "question": "After the execution of instruction \"RET \"",
    "options": [
      "SP is incremented by 2",
      "SP is incremented by 2",
      "SP is decremented by 2",
      "SP is incremented by 1",
      "SP is decremented by 1"
    ],
    "correct": "SP is incremented by 2",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "importance": 2
  },
  {
    "id": 106,
    "question": "The second byte in the word designated for one screen location holds",
    "options": [
      "Character color on the screen",
      "The dimensions of the screen",
      "Character position on the screen",
      "ASCII code of the character"
    ],
    "correct": "Character color on the screen",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "importance": 4
  },
  {
    "id": 107,
    "question": "REP will always",
    "options": [
      "Increment CX by 1",
      "Increment CX by 2",
      "Decrement CX by 1",
      "Decrement CX by 2"
    ],
    "correct": "Decrement CX by 1",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "importance": 2
  },
  {
    "id": 108,
    "question": "The basic function of SCAS instruction is to",
    "options": ["Compare", "Scan", "Sort", "Move data"],
    "correct": "Compare",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "importance": 5
  },
  {
    "id": 109,
    "question": "Index registers are used to store",
    "options": [
      "Data",
      "Intermediate result",
      "Address",
      "Both data and addresses"
    ],
    "correct": "Address",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "importance": 4
  },
  {
    "id": 110,
    "question": "The bits of the ______ work independently and individually",
    "options": [
      "index register",
      "base register",
      "flags register",
      "accumulator"
    ],
    "correct": "flags register",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "importance": 4
  },
  {
    "id": 111,
    "question": "To convert any digit to its ASCII representation",
    "options": [
      "Add 0x30 in the digit",
      "Subtract 0x30 from the digit",
      "Add 0x61 in the digit",
      "Subtract 0x61 from the digit"
    ],
    "correct": "Add 0x30 in the digit",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "importance": 2
  },
  {
    "id": 112,
    "question": "When a 32 bit number is divided by a 16 bit number, the quotient is of",
    "options": ["32 bits", "16 bits", "8 bits", "4 bits"],
    "correct": "16 bits",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "importance": 4
  },
  {
    "id": 113,
    "question": "When a 16 bit number is divided by an 8 bit number, the quotient will be in",
    "options": ["AX", "AL", "AH", "DX"],
    "correct": "AL",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "importance": 5
  },
  {
    "id": 114,
    "question": "Which mathematical operation is dominant during the execution of SCAS instruction",
    "options": ["Division", "Multiplication", "Addition", "Subtraction"],
    "correct": "Subtraction",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "importance": 4
  },
  {
    "id": 115,
    "question": "If AX contains decimal -2 and BX contains decimal 2 then after the execution of instructions: CMP AX, BX JA label",
    "options": [
      "Jump will be taken",
      "Zero flag will set",
      "ZF will contain value -4",
      "Jump will not be taken"
    ],
    "correct": "Jump will not be taken",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "importance": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 116,
    "question": "The execution of the instruction \"mov word [ES: 160], 0x1230\" will print a character \"0\" on the screen at",
    "options": [
      "Second column of first row",
      "First column of second row",
      "Second column of second row",
      "First column of third row"
    ],
    "correct": "Second column of second row",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "importance": 2
  },
  {
    "id": 117,
    "question": "If the direction of the processing of a string is from higher addresses towards lower addresses then",
    "options": ["ZF is cleared", "DF is cleared", "ZF is set", "DF is set"],
    "correct": "DF is set",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "importance": 5
  },
  {
    "id": 118,
    "question": "The instruction ADC has ______ Operand(s)",
    "options": ["0", "1", "2", "3"],
    "correct": "2",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "importance": 3
  },
  {
    "id": 119,
    "question": "Which bit of the attributes byte represents the red component of background color ?",
    "options": ["3", "4", "5", "6"],
    "correct": "6",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "importance": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 120,
    "question": "Suppose AL contains 5 decimal then after two left shifts produces the value as",
    "options": ["5", "10", "15", "20"],
    "correct": "20",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "importance": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 121,
    "question": "In STOS instruction, the implied source will always be in",
    "options": [
      "AL or AX registers",
      "DL or DX registers",
      "BL or BX registers",
      "CL or CX registers"
    ],
    "correct": "AL or AX registers",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "importance": 5
  },
  {
    "id": 122,
    "question": "After the execution of STOSW the CX will be",
    "options": [
      "Decremented by 1",
      "Decremented by 2",
      "Incremented by 1",
      "Incremented by 2"
    ],
    "correct": "Decremented by 1",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "importance": 2
  },
  {
    "id": 123,
    "question": "The basic function of SCAS instruction is to",
    "options": ["Compare", "Scan", "Sort", "Move data"],
    "correct": "Compare",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "importance": 3
  },
  {
    "id": 124,
    "question": "Which is the unidirectional bus ?",
    "options": [
      "(I) Control Bus",
      "(II) Data Bus",
      "(III) Address Bus",
      "I only",
      "II only",
      "III only",
      "I and II only"
    ],
    "correct": "III only",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "importance": 2
  },
  {
    "id": 125,
    "question": "The operation of CMP is to",
    "options": [
      "Subtract Source from Destination",
      "Subtract Destination to from Source",
      "Add 1 to the Destination",
      "Add Source and Destination"
    ],
    "correct": "Subtract Source from Destination",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "importance": 5
  },
  {
    "id": 126,
    "question": "The registers IP, SP, BP, SI, DI, and BX all can contain a ______ offset.",
    "options": ["8-bit", "16-bit", "32-bit", "64-bit"],
    "correct": "16-bit",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "importance": 5
  },
  {
    "id": 127,
    "question": "In assembly the CX register is used normally as a ______ register.",
    "options": ["source", "counter", "index", "pointer"],
    "correct": "counter",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "importance": 5
  },
  {
    "id": 128,
    "question": "All the addressing mechanisms in iAPX88 return a number called ______ register.",
    "options": ["effective", "faulty", "indirect", "direct"],
    "correct": "effective",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "importance": 3
  },
  {
    "id": 129,
    "question": "Which bit of the attributes byte represents the blue component of foreground color",
    "options": ["3", "2", "1", "0"],
    "correct": "0",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "importance": 4
  },
  {
    "id": 130,
    "question": "When a 32 bit number is divided by a 16 bit number, the quotient will be stored in",
    "options": ["AX", "BX", "CX", "DX"],
    "correct": "AX",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "importance": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 131,
    "question": "\"mov byte [num1], 5\" is ______ instruction.",
    "options": ["legal", "illegal", "stack based", "memory indirect"],
    "correct": "legal",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "importance": 2
  },
  {
    "id": 132,
    "question": "Which of the following options contain the set of instructions to open a window to the video memory?",
    "options": [
      "mov AX, 0xb008 mov ES, AX",
      "mov AX, 0xb800 mov ES, AX",
      "mov AX, 0x8b00 mov ES, AX",
      "mov AX, 0x800b mov ES, AX"
    ],
    "correct": "mov AX, 0xb800 mov ES, AX",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "importance": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 133,
    "question": "The execution of the instruction \"mov word [ES: 0], 0x0741\" will print character \"A\" on screen, color of the character will be",
    "options": ["Black", "White", "Red", "Blue"],
    "correct": "White",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "importance": 2
  },
  {
    "id": 134,
    "question": "Which of the following flags will be affected by MOVSW?",
    "options": ["DF", "PF", "ZF", "No effect on flags"],
    "correct": "No effect on flags",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "importance": 2
  },
  {
    "id": 135,
    "question": "Which bit of the attributes byte represents the blue component of background color ?",
    "options": ["3", "4", "5", "6"],
    "correct": "4",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "importance": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 136,
    "question": "To transfer control back the RET instruction take",
    "options": ["1 argument", "1 argument", "3 arguments", "No arguments"],
    "correct": "No arguments",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "importance": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 137,
    "question": "In STOSB instruction SI is decremented or incremented by",
    "options": ["4", "1", "2", "3"],
    "correct": "1",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "importance": 5
  },
  {
    "id": 138,
    "question": "CMPS instruction subtracts the source location to the destination location. Destination location always lies in",
    "options": ["DS:SI", "DS:DI", "ES:SI", "ES:DI"],
    "correct": "ES:DI",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "importance": 5
  },
  {
    "id": 139,
    "question": "Regarding assembler, which statement is true:",
    "options": [
      "Assembler converts mnemonics to the corresponding OPCODE",
      "Assembler converts OPCODE to the corresponding mnemonics",
      "Assembler executes the assembly code all at once",
      "Assembler executes the assembly code step by step"
    ],
    "correct": "Assembler converts mnemonics to the corresponding OPCODE",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "importance": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 140,
    "question": "If \"BB\" is the OPCODE of the instruction which states to \"move a constant value to AX register\", the hexadecimal representation (Using little Endian notation) of the instruction \"Mov AX,336\" (\"150\" in hexadecimal number system) will be:",
    "options": ["0xBB0150", "0x5001BB", "0x01BB50", "0xBB5001"],
    "correct": "0xBB5001",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "importance": 4
  },
  {
    "id": 141,
    "question": "In the instruction MOV AX, 5 the number of operands are",
    "options": ["1", "2", "3", "4"],
    "correct": "2",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "importance": 3
  },
  {
    "id": 142,
    "question": "The maximum parameters a subroutine can receive (with the help of registers) are",
    "options": ["6", "7", "8", "9"],
    "correct": "7",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "importance": 4
  },
  {
    "id": 143,
    "question": "In assembly the CX register is used normally as a ______ register.",
    "options": ["source", "counter", "index", "pointer"],
    "correct": "counter",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "importance": 5
  },
  {
    "id": 144,
    "question": "All the addressing mechanisms in iAPX88 return a number called ______ address.",
    "options": ["effective", "faulty", "indirect", "direct"],
    "correct": "effective",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "importance": 2
  },
  {
    "id": 145,
    "question": "When a 16 bit number is divided by an 8 bit number, the dividend will be in",
    "options": ["AX", "BX", "CX", "DX"],
    "correct": "AX",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "importance": 5
  },
  {
    "id": 146,
    "question": "in Left-Shift-Operation the left most bit",
    "options": [
      "will drop",
      "will go into CF",
      "Will come to the right most",
      "will be always 1"
    ],
    "correct": "will go into CF",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "importance": 3
  },
  {
    "id": 147,
    "question": "Suppose the decimal number \"35\" after shifting its binary two bits to left, the new value becomes",
    "options": ["35", "70", "140", "17"],
    "correct": "140",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "importance": 3
  },
  {
    "id": 148,
    "question": "When divide overflow occurs processor will be interrupted this type of interrupt is called",
    "options": [
      "Hardware interrupt",
      "Software interrupt",
      "Processor exception",
      "Logical interrupts"
    ],
    "correct": "Processor exception",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "importance": 4
  },
  {
    "id": 149,
    "question": "Which mathematical operation is dominant during the execution of SCAS instruction",
    "options": ["Division", "Multiplication", "Addition", "Subtraction"],
    "correct": "Subtraction",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Medium",
    "importance": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 150,
    "question": "After the execution of REP instruction CX will be decremented then which of the following flags will be affected?",
    "options": ["CF", "OF", "DF", "No flags will be affected"],
    "correct": "No flags will be affected",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Easy",
    "importance": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 151,
    "question": "______ is one of the reasons due to which string instructions are used in 8088",
    "options": [
      "Efficiency and accuracy",
      "Reduction in code size and accuracy",
      "Reduction in code size and speed",
      "Reduction in code size and efficiency"
    ],
    "correct": "Reduction in code size and speed",
    "explanation": "N/A",
    "difficulty": "Hard",
    "importance": 5
  }
]
